it is always important to have good
control of the instances that we are
using in our project but what would
happen if we could delimit a single
instance in the entire application to
certain objects in our project
this practice is known as the use
of the singleton pattern join me and let's go
to the code
[Music]
and today it's time to see the first
design pattern of the course known as
singleton and I would like to share with you two
pages in which this course is also
going to be based and that you can take
advantage of to strengthen the concepts that I
am going to explain and the first page is
source making in which on the
left hand side you will find a section
that says designs pater and it is separated
by what is the geo efe of make a
fork you have patterns that national
structural and behavioral 7
some examples the definition and also
the code so that you can check it out in
other programming languages for
example here we have the code in java in
php in python and among others another
well known page is tutorials point that
also has a section for
design patterns and explains many patterns
so that you can review their
ml diagram and an implementation  basic then I
recommend these two pages for you to
review throughout the
course check it out along with the examples
that are going to be created here on the channel the
following pattern as you are seeing here
this image ml connotation this class
that is above is
only intended to run the
application but it is not important in the
definition of the pattern itself this is the
important thing the single obviously a variable
called instance of the same type single or
and we also have a constructor a
method that instant that in the end will
return an object of the same class
single offset that is why you have a
return here so the objective of the
singleton pattern as you are seeing
here is to have a single instance of a
class throughout the application is that
all users use that
same instance but because you may
ask I will put the following
scenario imagine that you have
a list of countries to display
okay that list of countries is very
unlikely almost zero the possibility that they
can change the names then it would not make
sense to return to each
user that is achieved in our system
a memory space that is to say an object
which has the list of countries yes we
have 100 thousand users you will see  100
thousand objects
and they use the same information then it would
not make sense it would be better to have a
single object in which it has been
distanced only once and for each
user that needs this information
simply ask for the object that has already
been instantiated do perhaps by another
user obtain the same information
so 100,000 users are going to use
a single object and this in performance in
memory consumption is going to be much
better for this case I have brought an
example simulating the benefit if we
apply it to the jd issue you see in the
database we have a connection class
as you are seeing here an object called an
instance of the connection class which is the
same class that you are seeing here
we have it with a static and private scope
because gentlemen why because as we are going to
access its static methods without
going through an instance I need to
put the keyword static if you
do not know the use of this word
static I recommend you check the
basic tutorials of the channel in which
the differences between
instance methods and class methods are explained
and it will be very clear to you why
the reserved word static is used
I am going to create a constructor with a
private scope and this is the key to avoid
creating additional instances  look
when we put
private scope later when we want to
create an object we will not be able to
use the new operator if we will not be
able to do it then how do we obtain the
instance if the constructor is
private very easy I created a static type method
also so that it can be
accessed called get instance and here
I check if the instance is equal void
means that an object does not exist we are going
to distance what is fine and if for
some reason someone wants to continue
calling this method but a
previous user already instantiates it they would no longer enter
this step it would simply return the
instance that the previous user already
made these two methods are
simply test methods so that
you can see that I can access the
methods defined for
the class let's imagine that here we are
connecting to the database and here
disconnecting us then I have
my app class here thanks to the fact that I have put
the constructor in private scope I
cannot use the constructor as
simple as that
because it is not visible you can see
here it is in private scope and that is the
advantage of making it private because if we
had it in the traditional way
public you will see that here we will be
able to create an instance one by one
example and that each one instantiates two
then it wouldn't make sense because it would be
breaking the pattern so one
of the important steps is to place the
constructor as a private scope if we
want to have the instance, that is to say we
want to have an object of this
connection class we are going to rely on the
name of the class and connection in the
class itself and through the point I can
access the class method called
instance because this method has
static and allows me to directly
enter it yes and this as you already know
that it returns an instance no
agreement if it has been
previously distanced or not we are going to
have here in the variable ce already the
reference in memory of the
distanced object and that is why I can do
point connect and point disconnect we are going to
right click
frogs I connected to the database and I
disconnected from the database ok it
would have been very different if I had to
put public and here do it this
way I would have the same result here
yes gentlemen it would have the same result
but another user could do the
following no connection is one equal nor
connection and here I made one together connect I
made 1 point disconnect but here
how many instances would we have 2 1 2
so if we take this to a
larger scale when  we have many
users we are going to have many objects
for this same behavior so that is
why the singleton pattern is used and
having this advantage now what you are
seeing at the bottom instance
of connection is simply a plus
so you can see that what is being
returned from this method is really
an object of the connection class that is why I
have here I know that it is the variable it is an
instance of connection which is the class
this is going to return a value bull no longer
had falls and that is why you are seeing at
the bottom
true at the bottom you can see
a quote that says another example which is
practically the same implementation
of the pattern but with this topic of the
lists that I am telling you that is
in the advanced java 7 tutorials
if I am not mistaken and also people who
come from the world of spring and some of
my students who will take a
sprint course with me know that by default
sprint manages all its objects
called vince of singleton scope
when one does a
dependency injection it brings the
singleton instance of this object and as they are
usually used there to be able to
access data repositories as
all users want to access the
same repository  data bring the
same instance to be able to do its
operation another of the data that I
need as a conclusion is the
singleton design pattern allows to have a single
instance of a class to be
used throughout the application the
benefit is in performance
especially in memory the disadvantage
of this pattern is that we cannot abuse
it we are not going to do singleton
throughout the application there will be times
where a new instance is required to be
able to distinguish that the operation of the
user under not only sees it may vary in
some values we will talk precisely
about that implementation in a
design pattern known as prototype and also
the world of spring does not support do not
forget that this code will be
available in the git hub of the course so
see you in the next tutorial
that we will talk about the factory pattern and
then abstract factory if you liked
this tutorial give it a thumbs up
share it with your friends do not forget to
subscribe in the button below
follow me the social networks that are in
the description of the video leave your
comment and I will wait for you in a next
tutorial
[Music]